Your phone is tracking every move you
make, and until now, the police could
potentially use it to put you in
a crime scene without a proper warrant.
The United States Supreme Court just delivered
a massive win for your digital privacy
in the case of Chatrie versus United
States.
Police used a geofence warrant to scan
a 150 meter radius for anyone's phone
near a crime, eventually identifying three specific
accounts.
The government argued that short-term location data
isn't a search, but Justice Elena Kagan
disagreed, ruling that this data provides an
intimate window into your life.
This 6 to 3 ruling confirms that
accessing Google Location History is a Fourth
Amendment search, regardless of how long the
data was stored or who held it.
You have a reasonable expectation of privacy
in your location records.
Know your rights, and keep your data
secure.